http://www.nra.ie/privacy/

Home
Privacy Statement
Privacy
Introduction
We at TII respect your right to privacy and comply with our obligations under applicable data protection laws.  The purpose of this Website Privacy Statement is to outline how we deal with any personal data you provide to us while visiting this website.
Any external links to other websites are clearly identifiable as such, are provided for information purposes only and we are not responsible for the content, accuracy or the privacy statements of these other websites.
About Us
TII was established following the statutory merger of the National Roads Authority and the Railway Procurement Agency under the Roads Act 2015.  Our main address is Parkgate Business Centre, Parkgate Street, Dublin 8, D08 DK10, Ireland.
TII is the controller of personal data gathered through this website.  If you have any questions about our use of your personal data, please contact us at webfeedbackfwd@tii.ie, or contact our Data Protection Officer:
A. O’Shaughnessy,
Transport Infrastructure Ireland,
Parkgate Business Centre,
Parkgate Street,
Dublin 8,
D08 DK10.
Tel: +353 1 646 3600
Email: dataprotection@tii.ie
Purposes for which we hold your Information
We collect the following information about you via this website:
Information you provide to us
TII collects personal data relating to the TII Publications Updates Subscription service.  Such data is only collected from you if you voluntarily submit it via the TII Publications website at www.TIIPublications.ie.  Only the minimum amount of information necessary to provide you with the TII Publications Update Subscription service (i.e. an email address) is required.
TII collects personal data relating to Customer Service.  Such data is only collected from you if you submit it via the Customer Service Feedback form.  Only the minimum amount of information necessary to provide you with an answer to query (i.e. name, address, email address) is required.
TII collects personal data relating to the TII Web Application Portal.  Such data is only collected from you if you voluntarily submit it via the Portal website. Only the minimum amount of information necessary for registration is required.
Where a user voluntarily provides personal data in response to a questionnaire or survey the data will be used for research or analysis purposes only.
Your email address is also obtained where you contact TII using any of the email contact addresses contained within this website.  This is for the purpose of allowing TII to respond to your query.
Automatically collected data
We may gather statistical and other analytical information collected on an aggregate basis of visitors to our website. This includes demographic information regarding, for example, user IP addresses, browser types and other anonymous statistical data involving the use of our website. For information about the cookies we use to collect some of this information, please see our cookies policy here.
Purposes for which we hold your Information
Information you provide to us
We will process any personal data you provide to us for the following purposes:
to send you updates when a change has been made to the TII Publications by email;
to obtain feedback on the website and to respond to your feedback;
to respond to queries received via contact email addresses or feedback forms contained in this website; and
where you have opted-in, to contact you in relation to taking part in user surveys.
Automatically collected data
We use the automatically collected data that is gathered from visitors to our website in an aggregate form to get a better understanding of where our visitors come from and to help us better design and organise our website.
Basis for Processing
Our legal basis for collecting and using this information is that such processing is necessary for us to comply with our legal and regulatory obligations and for us to carry out our tasks in the public interest and/or in the exercise of official authority vested in us.  In certain limited circumstances our processing of your personal may be on the basis of your consent – where this is the case you will be asked to give a positive indication of that consent.
Disclosure of Information to Third Parties
We may disclose your personal data to other organisations in connection with the above purposes, in the following circumstances:
We may share personal data with service providers and sub-contractors who assist us with the operation of aspects of our services and functions, such as outsourced service providers, IT services providers, professional advisers and auditors.
If you send us a comment, complaint or query in relation to a matter that we are not responsible for, we will ask you permission to pass on your communication to the relevant third party.
Where we are under a duty to disclose or share personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or to protect the rights, property or safety of TII, our customers, or others.
Where we are otherwise permitted by law.
Transfers Abroad
In connection with the above TII may transfer your personal data outside the European Economic Area, including to a jurisdiction which is not recognised by the European Commission as providing for an equivalent level of protection for personal data as is provided for in the European Union. If and to the extent that TII does so, TII will ensure that appropriate measures are in place to comply with its obligations under applicable law governing such transfers, which may include entering into a contract governing the transfer which contains the ‘standard contractual clauses’ approved for this purpose by the European Commission and/or other transfer obligations/arrangements as may be specified by the Commission. Further details of the measures that TII has taken in this regard are available from the TII Data Protection Officer using the contact details below.
Security
Your personal data is held on secure servers hosted by TII.  The nature of the Internet is such that we cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us via the Internet.  No data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. However, we will take all reasonable steps (including appropriate technical and organisational measures) to protect your personal data.
Organisational Restructuring
We reserve the right to transfer information (including your personal data) in the event of a restructuring of our organisation to a third party which takes over the functions of our organisation, provided that the third party has an equivalent privacy policy in place
Updating, Verifying and Deleting Personal Data
Users can cancel their subscription to the TII Publications system at any time by clicking on the following link: http://TIIPublications.ie, and following the instructions at “Subscribe to TII alerts".
You may also inform us of changes or inaccuracies in your personal data by e-mailing webfeedbackfwd@tii.ie or by contacting our Data Protection Officer:
A. O’Shaughnessy,
Transport Infrastructure Ireland,
Parkgate Business Centre,
Parkgate Street,
Dublin 8,
D08 DK10.
Tel: +353 1 646 3600
Email: dataprotection@tii.ie
Retention
We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.
To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.
Your Rights
You have the following rights, in certain circumstances, in relation to your personal data:
the right to access your personal data;
the right to request the rectification and/or erasure of your personal data;
the right to restrict the use of your personal data;
the right to object to the processing of your personal data;
the right to receive your personal data, which you provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format or to require us to transmit that data to another data controller;
where our processing of your personal data is based on you having provided consent, the right to withdraw your consent to the processing at any time.
In order to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact our Data Protection Officer:
A. O’Shaughnessy,
Transport Infrastructure Ireland,
Parkgate Business Centre,
Parkgate Street,
Dublin 8,
D08 DK10.
Tel: +353 1 646 3600
Email: dataprotection@tii.ie
Complaints
If you are dissatisfied with the way we have used your information or addressed your rights, you have the right to make a complaint to the Data Protection Commission by emailing info@dataprotection.ie.
Social Media Privacy Statement
This statement relates to the privacy practices of Transport Infrastructure Ireland (TII) in connection with our social media accounts (e.g. Facebook, Twitter).  It sets out the basis on which any personal data that we collect from you, or that you supply to us, in connection with our social media accounts will be processed by us, in accordance with data protection law.  TII is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of the social media service providers.
General Statement
TII fully respects your right to privacy, and will process any personal data that we gather in relation to you in compliance with applicable data protection law.
About Us
TII was established following the statutory merger of the National Roads Authority and the Railway Procurement Agency under the Roads Act 2015.  Our main address is:
Parkgate Business Centre,
Parkgate Street,
Dublin 8,
D08 DK10.
TII is the controller of personal data gathered through this website.  If you have any questions about our use of your personal data, please contact us at webfeedbackfwd@tii.ie, or contact our Data Protection Officer:
A. O’Shaughnessy,
Transport Infrastructure Ireland,
Parkgate Business Centre,
Parkgate Street,
Dublin 8,
D08 DK10.
Tel: +353 1 646 3600
Email: dataprotection@tii.ie
Collection and use of personal information
TII will not collect any personally identifying information about you when you visit our social media accounts unless you choose to provide that information to us.  The information we collect depends on what you do when visiting our social media accounts.  For example, if you comment on a post with a complaint or a query we may record the content of your comment on our systems, or if you provide us with personal information such as contact details via a direct message we may record those details.
Our legal basis for collecting and using this information is that such processing is necessary for us to carry out our tasks in the public interest and/or in the exercise of official authority vested in us.
Disclosure of Information
We may disclose your personal data to other organisations in connection with the above purposes, in the following circumstances:
We may share personal data with service providers and sub-contractors who assist us with the operation of aspects of our services and functions, such as outsourced service providers, IT services providers, professional advisers and auditors.
If you send us a comment, complaint or query in relation to a matter that we are not responsible for, we will ask you permission to pass on your communication to the relevant third party.
Where we are under a duty to disclose or share personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or to protect the rights, property or safety of TII, our customers, or others.
Where we are otherwise permitted by law.
Transfers of Personal Data
In connection with the above TII may transfer your personal data outside the European Economic Area, including to a jurisdiction which is not recognised by the European Commission as providing for an equivalent level of protection for personal data as is provided for in the European Union.  If and to the extent that TII does so, TII will ensure that appropriate measures are in place to comply with its obligations under applicable law governing such transfers, which may include entering into a contract governing the transfer which contains the ‘standard contractual clauses’ approved for this purpose by the European Commission or, in respect of transfers to the United States of America, ensuring that the transfer is covered by the EU-US Privacy Shield framework.  Further details of the measures that TII has taken in this regard are available from the TII Data Protection Officer using the contact details below.
Retention
We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.
To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.
Your Rights
You have the following rights, in certain circumstances, in relation to your personal data:
the right to access your personal data;
the right to request the rectification and/or erasure of your personal data;
the right to restrict the use of your personal data;
the right to object to the processing of your personal data;
the right to receive your personal data, which you provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format or to require us to transmit that data to another data controller;
where our processing of your personal data is based on you having provided consent, the right to withdraw your consent to the processing at any time.
In order to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact our Data Protection Officer:
A. O’Shaughnessy,
Transport Infrastructure Ireland,
Parkgate Business Centre,
Parkgate Street,
Dublin 8,
D08 DK10.
Tel: +353 1 646 3600
Email: dataprotection@tii.ie
Complaints
If you are dissatisfied with the way we have used your information or addressed your rights, you have the right to make a complaint to the Data Protection Commission by emailing info@dataprotection.ie.
